Guide to the Adam M. Hallidy papers, 1862-1865 MS2042
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Adam M. Hallidy papers
1862-1865
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Hallidy, Adam M.
MS2042
0.25 Linear Feet
Collection consists of 14 handwritten letters, including 12 from Hallidy to his girlfriend Maggie, one from Maggie to Hallidy, and and a letter from his brother, Bob. Also contains 14 pages from Adam M. Hallidy's diary. The collection is arranged chronologically from 1862 to 1865.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition data is unknown for this collection.
Biographical Note
Adam M. Hallidy was a Union Army soldier during the Civil War and was in Company K, 2nd D.C. Volunteers. He married his friend Margaret sometime between August 1863 and May 1864. He mentions a cousin, Maggie, in New York, and indicates that Margaret had contact with her. It is unclear whether he is originally from New York, but mentions writing to his mother and three brothers. He makes no mention his occupation before the war or his plans after the war.
Scope and Content
The papers consist of 14 handwritten letters, as well as 14 pages from Adam M. Hallidy's diary. The collection is arranged chronologically from 1862 to 1865.
Twelve of the 14 letters are written by Hallidy to his girlfriend Maggie, who later became his wife. There is also one letter from her, as well as a letter from his brother, Bob. The letters and the diary deal with daily life and with Hallidy's experiences as a soldier. Of some note are his letters from October to December, 1862, as he writes from the hospital, after being transferred there with typhoid fever. He mentions missing the Battle of Antietam due to his illness.
Washington (D.C.); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Soldiers; Biography; Diaries; United States. Army
- Correspondence: to Maggie from Washington, DC, 1862 June 03 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: to Maggie from Carver Barracks Hospital, Washington, DC, 1862 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: to Maggie from Carver Barracks Hospital, Washington, DC, 1862 October 01 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: to Maggie from Mount Pleasant Hospital, Washington, DC, 1862 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: to Maggie from Cliffburn Barracks, Washington, DC, 1863 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: to Maggie from Cliffburn Barracks, Washington, DC, 1863 August 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: to Maggie, 1863 October 01 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: to Maggie, 1864-1865 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: to Maggie from Headquarters, 21 June, Washington, DC, 1864-1865 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Diary, 1864 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Diary, 1864 January 09-22 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: to wife, Maggie from Fairfax Courthouse, 1864 May 08 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: to brother Joe from brother Bob, 1864 July 04 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence: to wife, Maggie from Headquarters, Camp Sedgwick, Va, 1864 November 01 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence: to wife, Maggie from Alexandria, Va, 1864 December 30 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence: to Adam M. Hallidy from wife Margaret Hallidy, New York, 1865 January 05 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence: to wife, Maggie from Alexandria, Va, 1865 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence: to wife, Maggie from Alexandria, Va, 1865 August 09 (Box 1, Folder 18)